[音乐]
[MUSIC]
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：我刚才概述的这个攻击称为XSS攻击，
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: So this attack which I just outlined is called the XSS attack,
代表跨站点脚本。
which stands for cross site scripting.
现在它应该被称为CSS。
Now it should be called CSS.
但是还有另一个令人憎恶的东西叫做CSS。
But there was another abomination called CSS.
所以他们称它为XSS，但名称是个问题。
So they call it XSS but the name is a problem.
名字说跨站点描述有问题，但是
The name says that there's something wrong with cross-sitescripting but
事实上，这是一件非常可取的事情。
in fact that is a highly desirable thing.
我们希望能够有网站相互合作，业务和
We want to be able to have sites cooperate with each other and businesses and
服务相互协作，这些服务可能位于不同的站点上。
services cooperate with each other which might be located on different sites.
这是一件可取的事情，并不是一件坏事。
That's a desirable thing, it's not a bad thing.
并且这种攻击的形式不需要使用第二个站点。
And there are forms of this attack which do not require the use of a second site.
所以这个名字是完全错误的，但是安全专家首先
So the name is just completely wrong but the security experts who first
已确定此攻击不了解此攻击是什么。
identified this attack did not understand what this attack was.
他们给了一个不正确的名字，但是
They gave an incorrect name but
安全行业仍在使用这个名称，他们期待您成为
the security industry is still operating on that name, and they're expecting you as
当他们的语言不正确时，实践者要理解他们的意思。
practitioners to understand what they're meaning when their language is incorrect.
跨站点脚本攻击是在1995年JavaScript首次发布时发明的
Cross site scripting attacks were invented in 1995 when JavaScript was first released
从那以后他们就一直在继续。
and they've been going on ever since.
我们现在正处于跨站点脚本攻击的20周年纪念日。
We're just now on the 20th anniversary of cross site scripting attacks.
所以，我们已经迈出了一些小步。
So, we have made some baby steps.
例如，现在浏览器中有一个内容安全策略。
For example, there's a content security policy thing that's in browsers now.
花了很长时间才把它弄出来，但它就在那里。
It took a long time to get it out but it's out there.
不幸的是，大多数网站都没有使用它。
Unfortunately most sites aren't using it.
所以默认情况下它仍然是不安全的。
So it's still unsafe by default.
事实上，为了使用它，
And in fact, in order to use it,
这意味着很多常见的做法现在都变成了非法的，因为它们应该是非法的。
it means that a lot of common practices now become illegal, as they should.
但因为它们是常见的做法，它不会被使用。
But because they're common practices, it's not gonna get used.
mashup是一种自我造成的XSS攻击，
A mashup is a self-inflicted XSS attack,
事实证明，广告是一个混搭，而且
and it turns out advertising is a mashup, and
注入恶意代码最可靠、最具成本效益的方法是购买广告。
the most reliable cost effective method to inject evil code is to buy an ad.
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：那么为什么会有XSS呢？
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: So why is there XSS?
所以当架构层面出现问题时，
So when things go wrong at an architectural level,
永远不会只有一件事。
it's never just one thing.
你需要很多事情同时出错。
You need a lot of things to go wrong simultaneously.
这件事发生在网络上。
And that happened on the Web.
第一个是Web堆栈太复杂。
The first one is that the web stack is too complicated.
有太多的语言，每种语言都有自己的编码，引用，
There are too many languages, each with its own encoding, quoting,
注释和擒纵约定，它们都可以相互嵌套。
commenting and escapement conventions that can all be nested inside of each other.
我把这个叫做土耳其问题。
I've called this the turducken problem.
很难看到一段代码
It's very difficult to look at a piece of code and
确定它在所有情况下都是良性的。
determine that it's going to be benign in all contexts.
这是一个很难做的分析.
That's a very hard analysis to do..
而且它变得更糟了，因为浏览器做了英勇的
And it's made even worse because browsers do heroic
试图从格式错误的内容中找出有意义的东西。
things to try to make sense out of malformed content.
事实上，HTML5一开始就是试图将可怕的愚蠢行为标准化
In fact HTML5 began as an attempt to standardize the terrible stupid
浏览器试图解释无效HTML所做的事情。
things that browsers do to try to make sense of invalid HTML.
然后再加上基于模板的Web框架的流行
Then that's compounded with the popularity of template-based web frameworks that
针对XSS注入进行了优化。
are optimized for XSS injection.
我讨厌模板，我们稍后再讨论这些。
I hate templating, we'll talk more about those later.
最后，JavaScript全局对象给出了所有脚本片段
And then finally the JavaScript global object gives every scrap of script
同样强大的能力。
the same powerful capabilities.
但就像安全部门一样糟糕，
And yet as bad as it is at security,
浏览器仍然是对其他所有东西的巨大改进。
the browser is still a vast improvement over everything else.
所以问题不是跨站点脚本攻击。
So the problem is not a cross site scripting attack.
这是利益的混淆。
It is a confusion of interests.
浏览器区分用户和站点的兴趣，但是
The browser distinguishes between the interests of the user and of the site, but
它没有预料到可能会涉及其他利益。
it did not anticipate that there might be other interests involved.
这就是它失败的地方。
And that's where it fails.
所以页面内的兴趣是混乱的。
So within a page interests are confused.
所以一个广告，一个小部件，一个Ajax库，
So an ad, a widget, an AJAX library,
分析库，任何从第三方加载的东西，
an analytics library, anything that gets loaded from a third party,
所有这些代码都获得与您完全相同的权限。
all of that code gets exactly the same rights as you do.
这意味着你信任所有其他机构中的每个人。
It means you are trusting everybody in all of those other institutions.
现在JavaScript接近于正确地完成它
Now JavaScript gets close to getting it right and
我认为JavaScript可以修复并成为一种对象能力语言，
I think JavaScript can be repaired and become an object capability language,
我们将更多地讨论这意味着什么。
we'll talk more about what that means.
HTML，我对我们修复HTML没有任何希望
HTML, I don't have any hope that we're ever gonna fix HTML and
DOM是HTML使用可怕API，非常不安全。
the DOM which is that hideous API that HTML uses, is horribly insecure.
我也不认为这种感觉会消失。
I don't see that going away either.
所以这些东西不会很快修好。
So this stuff is not gonna get fixed in a hurry.
因此，由Web开发人员在不安全的环境中创建安全的应用程序
So it's up to web developers to create secure applications on an insecure
平台，这真的，真的很难。
platform and that is really, really hard.
它本不应该那么难，但它就是那么难。
It shouldn't have to be that hard but it is that hard.